# **Tshepo Gladwin Ramantso**

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

tshepo.ramantso@outook.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a highly driven Full Stack Web Developer, seeking to secure employment, to further develop and enhance my skills. I have a moderate to excellent knowledge of software development and product orientation design with 2 years of experience as a student mentor.

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3.

Back-End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, .

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Render, Mobile/Responsive Development, Node js, Figma, Chrome Dev Tools.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer

Remote Aug 2022 – Present

BlogApp - Fully functional website that will show the list of posts and empower readers to interact with them by adding comments and liking posts.

• Built with (Ruby on Rails, device and cancancan gems for Authentication and Authorization)

Math Magicians — An interactive and dynamic single-page app for math enthusiasts.

• Built with (React js, HTML5, CSS3)

To Do List —An interactive to-do list that allows users to add planned activities and delete those already accomplished.

Built with (HTML5, CSS3, ES6, Webpack)

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

Feb 2023 - Present

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organisation to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

#### HARMONY GOLD MINE

**Cost Accountant** 

Johannesburg, South Africa

Mar 2008 - Jul 2017

- Training all new and old incumbents on a step-by-step process on how to follow up on account reconciliations.
  - Restructuring of the Accounts Payable department and task allocation to team members.

#### **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE Nov 2022 – Mar 2024

### Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily stand-ups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

# UNIVERSITY OF JOHANNESBURG

Feb 2004 - Dec 2007

# Bcom, Accounting and Business Management

- Accounting, Auditing, Business Management, Taxation, Economics, Computer Information Science I.
- Certificate of merit for excellent achievement in Economics II (Macro Economics).